Kelsey Jacobsen | Designer

I'm a UI and UX designer with experience in end-to-end digital product design, from research to branding, mockups to front-end coding. Projects that excite me the most involve distilling information into slick visuals and pleasing micro-experiences.

Employment

UI/UX Designer | Roshi (Jan 2019-Present)

As the company's sole designer, I work to level up the MVP style guide and improve app usability. I do this while developing screen flows for new features for desktop, mobile, and tablet. I work with the Product Manager, Software Architect, CTO, and CEO. Example undertakings include:

- Problem- Outdated field design did not fit well on mobile, leading to user frustration with truncated text. Solution- Overhauled field design using Material-style floating labels, leading to positive user feedback.
- *Problem-* Users said that the filter UI was non-intuitive and took too many clicks to navigate. *Solution-* Redesigned filter component, reducing the number of required clicks from 7 to 3.
- Problem- Users found one module to be too long, with too much data entry and unclear terminology. Solution- Consolidated screens in the flow by 30%, auto-filled data where possible, and aligned all terminology.

Freelance Designer | Multiple clients (Sept 2019-Oct 2020)

I assisted clients with branding and digital experience design, including:

- World Resources Institute: For a new dashboard displaying global energy data, I guided a process to identify the key user stories to focus on and created low-fidelity dashboard mockups.
- Climate Adaptation Knowledge Exchange: I developed a look and feel for curriculum documents and created template assets.

Director (formerly Associate, then Senior Associate) | Blue Earth

Consultants, a Division of Eastern Research Group (Feb 2014-Feb 2019)

I led research, analysis, and writing of detailed reports and presentations for more than 30 non-profit, government, and foundation clients in the US and abroad. Working closely with clients, I wrote the strategic plans that guide their organizational efforts.

App Design Case Studies

Dively | kelseyjacobsen.design/dively

App for scuba divers: Concept, brand, mobile mockups, and animated flows

Dogear | kelseyjacobsen.design/dogear

App for writers: Concept, brand, and desktop and mobile prototypes

Education

Program in Digital Product Design | Bloc/Thinkful (2018-2019)

Completed 1,500+ hour, 11-month program with mentorship from seasoned designers; led end-to-end design process for two app concepts

Masters in Environmental Science and Management | Bren School, University of California, Santa Barbara (2010-2012)

www.kelseyjacobsen.design linkedin.com/in/kelseyingrid Alameda, CA

Design Focuses

- User stories and user flows
- High and low-fidelity mockups
- Prototyping
- User and preference testing
- Branding and style guides
- Design system implementation
- Basic HTML and CSS

Tools

- Sketch
- Figma
- Whimsical
- Zeplin
- Illustrator, InDesign, AfterEffects, LightRoom
- InVision
- Principle
- UsabilityHub
- Atom
- Git/GitHub
- Keynote, Pages, Numbers for Mac
- Microsoft PowerPoint, Word, Excel, Outlook
- Tableau

Other Interests

- Backcountry hiking
- Scuba diving
- Creating and selling illustrations
- Inventing recipes with farmers market vegetables